## **Marck Frience** Coto

Experienced front-end software engineer focused on building accessible digital experiences

**PROFILE** 

I am a front-end web developer with rich of **experience** in building freelance and personal projects. I am proficient in a variety of technologies, including **React**, Redux, Node, PHP, MySQL, **TypeScript** & MongoDB. I am also a strong **problem solver**, a **team player** and an **open-source** enthusiast.

## RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

#### 3D Modeller at Glimmertech

May 2023 — December 2024

- Identifying and labeling objects within a 3D environment.
- Analyzes 3D point clouds or meshes to assign semantic labels like "chair" or "wall" using specialized software, ensuring accurate segmentation for machine learning applications in autonomous navigation or virtual reality
- Correcting misclassifications and refining annotations to ensure consistent, accurate object identification for Al training and realistic 3D simulations.

# Manager – IT Technical Sales Specialists at Hube Computer July 2020 — Feb 2023

- I combine my leadership skills with a passion for design, creating visually engaging content while managing workflows to meet deadlines. This role allows me to enhance both the efficiency and aesthetic quality of our projects.
- I spearheaded the implementation of innovative sales strategies, leveraging technical expertise to drive a 20% increase in client acquisition and improve team performance through targeted training programs.

## Computer Technician, RAM Computer

Feb 2012 — April 2016

- Maintain, install and repair both software and hardware computer peripherals.
- Resolved technical issues, boosting system performance and customer satisfaction by 15%.

marckfriencec@gmail.com https://github.com/frience0 https://github.com/Unshack https://portfolio-ggt.vercel.app/ +63975-566-2423

## **SKILLS**

## **Programming Languages**

JavaSript, TypeScript, HTML, TailwindCSS, PHP, MongoDB

### **Libraries & Frameworks**

React, Next.js, Express, Vue, Laravel

#### **Tools & Version Control**

Git, GitHub, Netlify, Vercel, Render, Firebase, Figma

## SELECTED PROJECTS

## **Graphico Shirt Ecommerce**

An application powered by Next.js and MongoDB. Designed and implemented with a user-friendly interface to ensure a seamless

online shopping experience.

## **Gallant Property Homes**

A real estate platform for browsing land and building listings with a user-friendly interface and smooth search experience.

#### Saasify Application

A fullstack Saas website that helps user manage their online services.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **lligan Computer Institute**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

## **INTERESTS**

Hiking, drawing, web accessibility, coding